<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/blog/tag/hackverse/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2023-03-29T16:45:30+00:00</updated>
  <id>/blog/tag/hackverse/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">HackVerse Blog | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Hack It, Till You Crack it!</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">HackVerse’20: Behind The Scenes</title>
      <link href="/blog/behind-the-scenes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HackVerse’20: Behind The Scenes" />
      <published>2020-12-17T11:30:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-12-17T11:30:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/behind-the-scenes</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/behind-the-scenes">&lt;p&gt;HackVerse’20, the first edition of HackVerse (January 25-26, 2020) was the first in many regards. It was the first formal hackathon conducted by NITK Surathkal, and also the first to draw such a wide range of students from all across the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With over 2,400+ applicants for the one-day hackathon, the HackVerse organizing team, filled with eager and passionate students, was prepped and primed to welcome all the participants, judges, speakers, and guests and make them feel at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event involved keynotes and workshops by executives from renowned companies such as DigitalOcean, Elastic, Wells Fargo, as well as from startups like Devfolio. The hackathon offered cash prizes of over Rs 1.8 lakh to the top three teams, and other exciting rewards and prizes worth Rs 85 lakh to participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, instead of filling this article with paragraphs upon paragraphs of blandness, we shall explore and scout another way to get a glimpse into HackVerse’20. Let us hear from some of the people who helped make the largest student-run hackathon in India, HackVerse’20, come into existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-was-the-inspiration-behind-hackverse&quot;&gt;What was the inspiration behind HackVerse?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mishal Shah&lt;/em&gt;: “NITK didn’t have any hackathon. The ones that were conducted were on a small scale, and thus a lot of students in NITK didn’t have any experience of how amazing and impactful hackathons could be. We wanted to change this. We also wanted to help the hacker community grow. More number of organized hackathons empowers the developer community.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shreyas Shankar&lt;/em&gt;: “We wanted to start a college event on a national scale in the field of Computer Science, and what’s better than a hackathon where you can relax and code at the same time?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-planning-process&quot;&gt;The planning process…..?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Namrata Ladda&lt;/em&gt;: “It took almost two semesters to plan. Going through different articles and experiences and taking references from other hackathons helped.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sai Sushil&lt;/em&gt;: “The planning started at the college level initially. When we pitched it to the Dean (Students’ Welfare), his suggestion was to put together a nationwide hackathon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mishal Shah&lt;/em&gt;: “The planning process started in June 2019. We had a lot of meetings and discussions. It was complete synergy, with all the team members pitching in with inventive ideas and suggestions. We had attended various hackathons before and had a brief idea of what to do. We studied how some of the best hackathons in the world were organized and tried to incorporate those ideas in HackVerse. Our main focus was on hacker experience!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;expectations-and-hopes-from-hackverse20&quot;&gt;Expectations and hopes from HackVerse’20?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polkampally Keerthana&lt;/em&gt;: “We wanted HackVerse’20 to be phenomenal with a huge turnout. We especially wanted participants to have a good time and learn new things.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mishal Shah&lt;/em&gt;: “Hackers coming to NITK and having a good time was my dream. I was hoping that they would network with other hackers and organizers, continue working on their idea after the hackathon and learn new and fascinating things. We wished to empower hackers through talks, networking, or building.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-moment-you-realized-that-what-you-had-built-was-coming-to-fruition&quot;&gt;The moment you realized that what you had built was coming to fruition…?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polkampally Keerthana&lt;/em&gt;: “The morning when participants started arriving for registration. It felt surreal when I thought about how a team of students had organised a nationwide hackathon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shreyas Shankar&lt;/em&gt;: “The moment we got to the mark we expected in sponsorship and became the hackathon with the highest number of registrations in India. I felt immense pride.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mishal Shah&lt;/em&gt;: “The hackathon feedback! Reading the feedback from the judges, speakers, and hackers just blew my mind! Many of them pronounced that our hackathon was unique; there were things that they had never seen in all the previous hackathons that they had attended.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-kind-of-difficulties-did-you-face-in-organising-the-event&quot;&gt;What kind of difficulties did you face in organising the event?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sai Sushil&lt;/em&gt;: “For me, the biggest obstacle was not being from a CS/IT background. Nonetheless, I learned a lot and was able to contribute with the help of my teammates.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polkampally Keerthana&lt;/em&gt;: “Every phase had its difficulties. From deciding the judges, selecting the participants to last-minute changes on the event day; they all seemed like insurmountable odds until we conquered them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;something-new-that-you-learned-as-a-part-of-team-hackverse20&quot;&gt;Something new that you learned as a part of Team HackVerse’20?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mishal Shah&lt;/em&gt;: “Marketing, building an event from scratch and organising it, team management and communication skills. We also learned how to take risks and overcome challenges by organising this hackathon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adarsh Malapaka&lt;/em&gt;: “The saying ‘Too many cooks spoil the broth’ is true. Don’t let too many people be in charge of the same task. Establish a chain of command.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-was-the-best-part-of-the-event&quot;&gt;What was the best part of the event?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pavan Vachhani&lt;/em&gt;: “The satisfaction and sense of achievement we felt after the successful completion of the event.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mehnaz Yunus&lt;/em&gt;: “Working with a great team and successfully pulling off an event of this scale.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Namrata Ladda&lt;/em&gt;: “Interacting with the participants, guests, and speakers were the best part.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mishal Shah&lt;/em&gt;: “The mini-gaming arena. A lot of hackers loved it, there was always someone or the other playing there, and that made it worth all the effort we put in it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adarsh Malapaka&lt;/em&gt;: “Being able to connect with different companies, participants, and other professionals during the event.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-in-your-opinion-made-hackverse20-a-success&quot;&gt;What, in your opinion, made HackVerse’20 a success?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Namrata Ladda&lt;/em&gt;: “The team’s desire to host the event in the best way possible, and the support received from the faculty advisors of HackVerse (Dr. Anand Kumar M, Dr. Sowmya Kamath, Dr. Suprabha K R), Diamond Jubilee Chairman (Dr. S. M. Murigendrappa Sir), Dean SW (Dr. Jagannath Nayak), Director (Prof. K Uma Maheshwar Rao), BoG Chairman (Dr. K Balaveera Reddy) and the whole of NITK Administration with all the help needed to set up the event truly made it possible.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sai Sushil&lt;/em&gt;: “Support and recognition from all over India. And the fact that we all worked day and night, contributing in any way we could.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adarsh Malapaka&lt;/em&gt;: “I believe that HackVerse’20 was a success because we made no compromise on the technical side of the event, despite the inauguration ceremony and webinars eating into the hacking time. Secondly, we took good care of our participants with the SPoCs (Student Point of Contact) and the PR (Public Relations) team doing a fantastic job of being approachable, proactive and making the participants feel comfortable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polkampally Keerthana&lt;/em&gt;: “Teamwork, co-operation, delegating tasks, taking up responsibility, working hard, and not giving up at any point.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-advice-would-you-give-to-a-student-applying-for-hackverse&quot;&gt;What advice would you give to a student applying for HackVerse?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Akash&lt;/em&gt;: “Hackathons are an excellent opportunity to meet brilliant and tech-savvy people from all walks of life; build your profile as a hacker, and create something extraordinary that will improve lives. Don’t miss out on this opportunity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shreyas Shankar&lt;/em&gt;: “My advice would be to have a good number of open source contributions, high-quality and legitimate projects, a well-defined Readme on Github, previous hackathon experiences and a solid, innovative idea which appeals to the reviewer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polkampally Keerthana&lt;/em&gt;: “Be genuine with your resume and the questions asked during the application.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-advice-would-you-give-to-someone-organising-an-event-like-hackverse&quot;&gt;What advice would you give to someone organising an event like HackVerse?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adarsh Malapaka&lt;/em&gt;: “It might sound banal, but ‘where there’s a will, there’s a way’ is probably the most golden advice for organising an event, however big or small. Ensure that the team is firmly committed and excited about the prospect of having this event. If you want the pearl from the ocean, you can’t merely caress the waves and rush back to the sands of safety. You have to dive deep, being dynamic to potential threats.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mehnaz Yunus&lt;/em&gt;: “Be an early bird. Try to do everything ahead of time. Get good judges, confirm them as soon as possible. Set up good judging criteria and a plagiarism checking system, if possible. Develop a social media presence. Be prompt in responding to queries from participants and keep their data safe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sai Sushil&lt;/em&gt;: “Push your boundaries, explore new possibilities and never stop making it better even when it seems good enough.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pavan&lt;/em&gt;: “Think thoroughly about the timeline of the event. Count even the smallest things.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Polkampally Keerthana&lt;/em&gt;: “Do not panic. Just give it some time, come back and try again. And most importantly, organize your thoughts. Be clear about your goals.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, folks, is how we made HackVerse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve got an idea of how we did it, it’s time to spread the word. Nothing promotes growth like competition, and hackathons bring out the best in us, from our team building and management skills to ingenuity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startups regularly get developed in hackathons and wind up getting millions in funding and launch lucrative careers - Twitter is living proof. We deemed it our duty to provide that challenge for students, on the Diamond Jubilee Celebrations of NITK, to promote our hackathon as well as the coding culture of our campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is how the story ends… or does it?&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>[&quot;shumbul&quot;, &quot;kriti&quot;, &quot;feyaz&quot;]</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="hackverse" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">HackVerse’20, the first edition of HackVerse (January 25-26, 2020) was the first in many regards. It was the first formal hackathon conducted by NITK Surathkal, and also the first to draw such a wide range of students from all across the nation.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">HackVerse’20 API Prizes and Hacks!</title>
      <link href="/blog/hackverse20-hack-ideas" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HackVerse'20 API Prizes and Hacks!" />
      <published>2020-01-19T10:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-01-19T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/hackverse20-hack-ideas</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/hackverse20-hack-ideas">&lt;p&gt;All set for the Hackathon but still running short of ideas, we have something in store for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We present to you, API prizes from our sponsors Matic and Zulip. Build on top of these to win exciting prizes! You can find more details of their prizes and guidelines in the following links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: circle;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://paper.dropbox.com/doc/Matic-Ethereum-Track-Prize-FToXnL0x0THdKv7C3PaT9&quot;&gt;Matic Etherium API Prize&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Rs.20000 to best hack built on Ethereum &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Rs. 25000 if Matic is also used along with Ethereum &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://paper.dropbox.com/doc/Zulip-Bot-Prize-vZuqxEnsfhEReqKucdlfB&quot;&gt;Zulip API Prize&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;$100 for the best bot built on top of Zulip&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team has compiled a variety of ideas, and it might as well be the key to you winning the hackathon. The ideas metiones below are meant to be a source of inspiration and is open to interpretation and implementation. Feel free to add in your own unique ideas and modifications to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blockchain&quot;&gt;Blockchain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elections are under threat from malicious actors that can infiltrate voting machines, alter voter registration databases, coordinated disinformation campaigns, and more. How can you use Blockchain to secure the process?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intellectual Property : with Blockchain projects creative individuals can have the opportunity to share their content online and be able to prove that they are indeed the creators of said content and hold all intellectual property rights regardless of where it ends up, and everyone else would be aware of this too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charitable organizations are obviously a good thing, especially when they actually use their funds for the intended purposes, which is typically to help people. Unfortunately, that is not always the case, and there have been situations in which charitable organizations have been labeled as corrupt and have been involved in unethical activities. Blockchain technology can help remedy this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digital IDs : More than 1 billion people worldwide face identity challenges. Creating digital IDs which would give users a way to control their digital identities. Medical recordkeeping: The good news is the medical sector has already been moving away from paper for recordkeeping purposes for years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;However, blockchain offers even more safety and convenience. In addition to storing patient records, the patient, who possesses the key to access these digital records, would be in control of who gains access to that data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weapons tracking : One of the hot-button topics on any news network at the moment is gun control and/or weapons accountability. Blockchain could create a transparent and unchanging registry network that allows law enforcement and the federal government to track gun or weapon ownership, as well as keep a record of weapons sold privately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;aiml&quot;&gt;AI/ML&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A system which can do a check-up for emergencies and give short term advice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Classifying articles or news stories as potentially misleading or not.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agriculture has transformed with the advent of irrigation, but irrigation itself requires a certain level of supervision. Develop Irrigation systems which self regulate according to weather patterns.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Depression affects about 20% of adolescents by the time they become adults. Develop Interfaces or chatbots that can help counsel people with issues like depression or anxiety issues and suicidal tendencies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personal Health Assistant : The AI in your phone will figure out exactly when and how to wake you up given your health, sleep patterns and time constraints. It will also look into your eating habits and suggest you restaurants and dishes for keeping you in track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;algorithms&quot;&gt;Algorithms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you devise new algorithms to improve the control of vehicular traffic in crowded cities?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin – last year it was claimed that the computing power required to keep the network running consumes as much energy as was used by 159 of the world’s nations. Come up with an implementation which solves the energy problem with your own Consensus algorithm.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An app for taxi drivers- which will help them to identify which locations to concentrate and go around in loops in order to get maximum customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fin-tech&quot;&gt;Fin-Tech&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digital Banking:  Enable after-hours banking services with an interactive interface using chatbots and video capabilities. Leveraging on technology to build personal teller service for banking transactions or professional banking consultations for customers after business hours as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alternative Credit Rating: Access to finance &amp;amp; banking facilities remains limited for the unbanked population &amp;amp; businesses in remote areas. A financial/banking app could potentially bridge this gap by sourcing information that can contribute to an alternative credit rating, and subsequently allow other institutions to leverage on it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cashback @ Merchants: Finding an ATM can be a challenge and sometimes they may not be in service. Design a solution that allows the withdrawal and deposit of cash from merchants for easier access to cash.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invoice financing: Invoice duplication and fraud cases in invoice financing can be mitigated by creating a database leveraging on a unique ID for each invoice/document.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learning Interface for All: Understanding banking instruments and financial systems remains a challenge in Tier 2-3 and rural areas due to language and smartphone usage barriers. Develop a digital solution for awareness generation for this segment to be able to understand and access relevant financial instruments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Financial and Wealth Management: Wealth Management is resorted to only by the Upper-Class Indians who have significant savings to invest in Alternative Funds. Financial Planning and investment of savings by the middle class and youth is very low. Develop a solution to increase middle class and younger generation participation in Financial Markets to leverage investment of savings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;future-mobility&quot;&gt;Future Mobility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Study of flow dynamics of people within a city to improve public transport infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monitoring the driver to keep them alert at all times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Detecting unavoidable Frontal, Rear end, T-bone, and other types of collisions to activate preventive measures.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mycardoeswhat.org datasets as a source of inspiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;computer-vision&quot;&gt;Computer Vision&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Written documents to pdf converter application.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Differentiating between recyclable and nonrecyclable was which can be used by robots for automating cleaning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing systems that can detect crimes happening from live CCTV feed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play from sheet music.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Class attendance and attention monitoring.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bill splitting with the product and person identification from photos(user need not manually mention items bought by individuals)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use satellite images to count number of trees and track deforestation and alert authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Smart projection system with presenter detection: Use a camera to detect if the presenter is covering the projection. Use this for assisting the presenter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ar-vr&quot;&gt;AR-VR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing Virtual reality Technology which can help children interact and help them in studying different subjects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Augmented reality models with labeling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Making Technical Documentation using AR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;open-innovation&quot;&gt;Open Innovation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Product Costing is an important procedure of business, which helps them to approximate the cost of making a product, Design a system to simplify the same.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Incorrect diagnosis in hospitals often leads to tragic deaths, due to wide information gap between doctors and patients, which makes the patients susceptible to whatever the doctor recommends. How can you help overcome this rising problem?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rural medical care- Medical care in the villages is barely sufficient and lacking in a lot of facilities, which leads to an unfair amount of deaths, how can this be solved?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other good inspiration, we suggest &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/tsaqib/9a8ded18603881b76a8f&quot;&gt;this page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mlsdev.com/blog/top-10-problems-that-blockchain-technology-solves&quot;&gt;https://mlsdev.com/blog/top-10-problems-that-blockchain-technology-solves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fool.com/investing/2018/04/11/20-real-world-uses-for-blockchain-technology.aspx&quot;&gt;https://www.fool.com/investing/2018/04/11/20-real-world-uses-for-blockchain-technology.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-real-life-problems-will-be-solved-with-Artificial-Intelligence-AI-within-the-next-10-years-i-e-by-2028&quot;&gt;https://www.quora.com/What-real-life-problems-will-be-solved-with-Artificial-Intelligence-AI-within-the-next-10-years-i-e-by-2028&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2018/02/19/the-5-big-problems-with-blockchain-everyone-should-be-aware-of/#71cbc3fa1670&quot;&gt;https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2018/02/19/the-5-big-problems-with-blockchain-everyone-should-be-aware-of/#71cbc3fa1670&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/tsaqib/9a8ded18603881b76a8f&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/tsaqib/9a8ded18603881b76a8f&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iotworldtoday.com/2016/06/29/10-killer-applications-iot-and-augmented-reality/&quot;&gt;https://www.iotworldtoday.com/2016/06/29/10-killer-applications-iot-and-augmented-reality/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>[&quot;vybhav&quot;, &quot;rahul&quot;, &quot;shubham&quot;]</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="hackverse" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">All set for the Hackathon but still running short of ideas, we have something in store for you!</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Why Attend Hackathons</title>
      <link href="/blog/why-attend-hackathons" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Attend Hackathons" />
      <published>2019-12-13T01:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-12-13T01:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/why-attend-hackathons</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/why-attend-hackathons">&lt;p&gt;Learn more about why you should attend hackathons and what makes HackVerse special!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-a-hackathon&quot;&gt;What is a hackathon?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A hackathon, a hacker neologism, is an event when programmers meet to do collaborative computer programming.” - &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackathon&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackathons are awesome places to build solutions to real-world problems and express the creativity through technology within a short period of time, with like-minded enthusiastic people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-should-you-attend-hackathons&quot;&gt;Why should you attend hackathons?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-things-that-matter&quot;&gt;Create things that matter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that “GroupMe” a group messaging app acquired by Skype for over $50 million was built during a hackathon? Or the Facebook “Like” button &amp;amp; Facebook chat being built in an internal company hackathon?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./assets/images/why-attend/groupme-fb.png&quot; alt=&quot;GroupMe &amp;amp; Facebook&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been countless similar examples that show that hackathons are serious events that can potentially have a long-lasting impact on our day to day lives. And we expect each and everyone coming here to aim for a similar impact, nothing less!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;acquire-art-of-delivery&quot;&gt;Acquire Art of Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember Yahoo Answers before the era of Quora?  Or pets.com?
In the real world, the delivery and presentation of a product is equally important if not more important than the code itself. However, this is not something that is ever taught to us. Hackathons will teach you the importance of this art, and you surely do not want to miss out on that, do you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-win-or-you-learn&quot;&gt;You Win or You Learn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can interact with awesome programmers from various backgrounds and observe their ideas, thought process and approach. It is a fantastic opportunity to broaden your mind and learn a lot, be it the state-of-the-art technology or the newest libraries in the field of your choice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-attend-hackverse&quot;&gt;Why attend HackVerse?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackathons are really exciting places to be, and HackVerse aims to take it a whole new level!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re really excited to be a part of this hackathon! And you should be too! We’ve got a great team, great sponsors, and lots of great ideas bubbling. To make sure you fully enjoy yourself in this hackathon and make the most of the occasion, here are some things you might want to keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;most-importantly-to-have-fun&quot;&gt;Most importantly to have FUN&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be it the adrenaline rush during the last 15 minutes of building, meeting like-minded geeks, NITK’s private beach, some cultural events, some really fun activities at night or the lush greenery spread across 300 acres, you will have something to enjoy every moment here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./assets/images/nitk/aerial-kite-fest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NITK Beach&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./assets/images/why-attend/bd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cultural Event&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;workshops&quot;&gt;Workshops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HackVerse will be having some workshops from the executives from industry and those surely will be a boost to your knowledge. It’ll help you get real-world knowledge and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boost-your-resume&quot;&gt;Boost your Resume&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most companies and startups prefer enthusiastic students who have built innovative solutions using the latest technologies to solve real-world problems. The prototype you exhibit here, could potentially boost your resume and enable you to stand apart from the crowd. Who knows what your idea can become? Maybe you’ll build the next “GroupMe”, Maybe you might get hired?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;network-network-and-network&quot;&gt;Network, Network, and Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackathons are a great place to meet like-minded people and exchange ideas, insights and collaborate. HackVerse has introduced a trademark event called &lt;strong&gt;Meet-and-Greet&lt;/strong&gt;. This session will be completely dedicated to meeting other participants and mentors. You can meet new people, make new friends, get to listen to different perspectives, clarify your doubts and get guidance from mentors. In short, this session is aimed to help you build a strong network with people across all regions, fields, and experience, which we believe will help you in the long run, even after the hackathon is over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./assets/images/why-attend/networking.png&quot; alt=&quot;Networking&quot; height=&quot;70%&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prizes&quot;&gt;Prizes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all of this, Prizes are the last thing one would look for. Prizes although may seem like great motivators but they are ineffective at building communities and creating long-term enegagement. If a hackathon prize is too large, people who hack because of passion will likely be turned off. Focusing too much on prizes can make those who are there out of passion or to learn something new feel like their experience is not valued by their peers or the event organizers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You get to be with people who are passionate about tech just like you or more than you for 24 hours. That is the best place you wanna be (like heaven).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We assure there are huge prizes in terms of cash and the swags for the winners and everyone who attends, but we don’t recommend attending HackVerse or any other hackathon solely for prizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ethos of HackVerse is thus to bring the experience of hackathon to you, give you a platform where you can  learn and excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are you waiting for! Unleash your skills and show us that you deserve to be here. Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackverse.nitk.ac.in&quot;&gt;https://hackverse.nitk.ac.in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join our Telegram Group to meet other like minded hackers: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/hackverse&quot;&gt;https://t.me/hackverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;references--credits&quot;&gt;References &amp;amp; Credits&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/hackathons-anonymous/wtf-is-a-hackathon-92668579601&quot;&gt;WTF is a hackathon?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/tfogo/hackathons-are-for-beginners-77a9c9c0e000&quot;&gt;Hackathons are for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.mlh.io/are-hackathon-prizes-the-worst-thing-since-moldy-sliced-bread-04-18-2014&quot;&gt;Are Hackathon Prizes The Worst Thing Since Moldy Sliced Bread?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Picture Credits: &lt;a href=&quot;https://appmech.nitk.ac.in/faculty/pruthviraj-u&quot;&gt;Prof. Pruthiviraj Umesh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>[&quot;shravan&quot;]</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="hackverse" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Learn more about why you should attend hackathons and what makes HackVerse special!</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Tips for Outstation Participants</title>
      <link href="/blog/tips-for-outstation-participants" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tips for Outstation Participants" />
      <published>2019-11-23T01:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-11-23T01:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/tips-for-outstation-participants</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/tips-for-outstation-participants">&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on getting selected for HackVerse ‘20!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are super excited to host you at our campus, NITK, Surathkal and we look forward to meeting you and see what you create!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is aimed to give you a few tips and suggestions so that your journey to HackVerse, NITK, Surathkal and stay here is as hassle free as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we proceed ahead, take a look at the beautiful campus you’re going to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NITKians proudly flaunt about being the only college in India to have a private beach, and it’s your chance to spend a weekend coding, and working on an idea nearby the beach and enjoy the other programs planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./assets/images/nitk/aerial-beach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NITK, Surathkal Beach&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./assets/images/nitk/aerial-kite-fest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NITK, Surathkal Beach&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;accomodation&quot;&gt;Accomodation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All outstation participants will be provided accommodation at NITK, Surathkal for all the 3 days - 24th to 26th of January. Matresses will be provided for a comfortable sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reaching-nitk&quot;&gt;Reaching NITK&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NITK, Surathkal is a lush green campus on the shores of the Arabian sea, nourished and blessed by the monsoon showers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./assets/images/nitk/aerial-nitk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Green Aerial NITK Surathkal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many options to travel to the campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;travelling-through-train&quot;&gt;Travelling Through Train&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan to travel to NITK, Surathkal by train, following are the primary railway stations nearby the campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mangalore Junction (Station Code: MAJN)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mangalore Central (Station Code: MAQ)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surathkal (Station Code: SL)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are frequent local bus services from these stations to reach NITK, Surathkal which provide services at a very afforadable cost - less than Rs. 30. Participants are suggested to take a local bus from the railway station. Local Bus services start as early as 6 am in the morning, and are available at every 5-10 mins interval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;travelling-through-flight&quot;&gt;Travelling Through Flight&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan to travel to NITK, Surathkal by a flight, the nearest airport to NITK, Surathkal is the Mangalore Airport at a distance of around 20 kms. Taxi services are available from the airport to reach NITK, Surathkal. They usually take 30 mins maximum to reach the campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;travelling-through-bus&quot;&gt;Travelling Through Bus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For participants in and around Mangalore, Udupi or Manipal, there are plenty of local buses which ply very frequently from the main gate. You can reach NITK very easily using these services.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For participants from Bangalore and Mysore, there a plenty of bus services available (SRS, Orange, VRL, Durgamba, Pragathi etc). These buses generally stop right in front of NITK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope this helps you figure out the logistics of getting to NITK, Surathkal. If you have any further doubts, please join our Telegram Group, one of the organizers will help you out. Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/hackverse&quot;&gt;https://t.me/hackverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t wait to meet you at the hacking arena and see what you create!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./assets/images/nitk/lhcc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;LHC-C NITK Surathkal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checkout some amazing clicks of our campus:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;carousel__holder&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;carousel&quot;&gt;
        
          &lt;input class=&quot;carousel__activator&quot; type=&quot;radio&quot; name=&quot;carousel&quot; id=&quot;a&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;
        
          &lt;input class=&quot;carousel__activator&quot; type=&quot;radio&quot; name=&quot;carousel&quot; id=&quot;b&quot; /&gt;
        
          &lt;input class=&quot;carousel__activator&quot; type=&quot;radio&quot; name=&quot;carousel&quot; id=&quot;c&quot; /&gt;
        
          &lt;input class=&quot;carousel__activator&quot; type=&quot;radio&quot; name=&quot;carousel&quot; id=&quot;d&quot; /&gt;
        
          &lt;input class=&quot;carousel__activator&quot; type=&quot;radio&quot; name=&quot;carousel&quot; id=&quot;e&quot; /&gt;
        
        
          
          
          
          
          &lt;div class=&quot;carousel__controls&quot;&gt;
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__control carousel__control--backward&quot; for=&quot;e&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__control carousel__control--forward&quot; for=&quot;b&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        
          
          
          
          
          &lt;div class=&quot;carousel__controls&quot;&gt;
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__control carousel__control--backward&quot; for=&quot;a&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__control carousel__control--forward&quot; for=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        
          
          
          
          
          &lt;div class=&quot;carousel__controls&quot;&gt;
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__control carousel__control--backward&quot; for=&quot;b&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__control carousel__control--forward&quot; for=&quot;d&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        
          
          
          
          
          &lt;div class=&quot;carousel__controls&quot;&gt;
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__control carousel__control--backward&quot; for=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__control carousel__control--forward&quot; for=&quot;e&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        
          
          
          
          
          &lt;div class=&quot;carousel__controls&quot;&gt;
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__control carousel__control--backward&quot; for=&quot;d&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__control carousel__control--forward&quot; for=&quot;a&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel__track&quot;&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
            
            &lt;li class=&quot;carousel__slide&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url('./assets/images/nitk/aerial-campus.jpg');&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            
            &lt;li class=&quot;carousel__slide&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url('./assets/images/nitk/aerial-cse.jpg');&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            
            &lt;li class=&quot;carousel__slide&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url('./assets/images/nitk/kite-fest.jpg');&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            
            &lt;li class=&quot;carousel__slide&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url('./assets/images/nitk/entrance.png');&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            
            &lt;li class=&quot;carousel__slide&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url('./assets/images/nitk/aerial-mech.jpg');&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            
          &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel__indicators&quot;&gt;
            
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__indicator&quot; for=&quot;a&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
            
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__indicator&quot; for=&quot;b&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
            
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__indicator&quot; for=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
            
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__indicator&quot; for=&quot;d&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
            
              &lt;label class=&quot;carousel__indicator&quot; for=&quot;e&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
.carousel__holder {width: 100%; position: relative; padding-bottom: 50%; margin: 1rem 0 1rem;}
.carousel {
  height: 100%;
  width: 100%;
  overflow: hidden;
  text-align: center;
  position: absolute;
  padding: 0;
}
.carousel__controls,
.carousel__activator {
  display: none;
}

.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(1):checked ~ .carousel__track {
  -webkit-transform: translateX(-000%);
          transform: translateX(-000%);
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(1):checked ~ .carousel__slide:nth-of-type(1) {
  transition: opacity 0.5s, -webkit-transform 0.5s;
  transition: opacity 0.5s, transform 0.5s;
  transition: opacity 0.5s, transform 0.5s, -webkit-transform 0.5s;
  top: 0;
  left: 0;
  right: 0;
  opacity: 1;
  -webkit-transform: scale(1);
          transform: scale(1);
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(1):checked ~ .carousel__controls:nth-of-type(1) {
  display: block;
  opacity: 1;
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(1):checked ~ .carousel__indicators .carousel__indicator:nth-of-type(1) {
  opacity: 1;
}

.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(2):checked ~ .carousel__track {
  -webkit-transform: translateX(-100%);
          transform: translateX(-100%);
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(2):checked ~ .carousel__slide:nth-of-type(2) {
  transition: opacity 0.5s, -webkit-transform 0.5s;
  transition: opacity 0.5s, transform 0.5s;
  transition: opacity 0.5s, transform 0.5s, -webkit-transform 0.5s;
  top: 0;
  left: 0;
  right: 0;
  opacity: 1;
  -webkit-transform: scale(1);
          transform: scale(1);
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(2):checked ~ .carousel__controls:nth-of-type(2) {
  display: block;
  opacity: 1;
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(2):checked ~ .carousel__indicators .carousel__indicator:nth-of-type(2) {
  opacity: 1;
}

.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(3):checked ~ .carousel__track {
  -webkit-transform: translateX(-200%);
          transform: translateX(-200%);
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(3):checked ~ .carousel__slide:nth-of-type(3) {
  transition: opacity 0.5s, -webkit-transform 0.5s;
  transition: opacity 0.5s, transform 0.5s;
  transition: opacity 0.5s, transform 0.5s, -webkit-transform 0.5s;
  top: 0;
  left: 0;
  right: 0;
  opacity: 1;
  -webkit-transform: scale(1);
          transform: scale(1);
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(3):checked ~ .carousel__controls:nth-of-type(3) {
  display: block;
  opacity: 1;
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(3):checked ~ .carousel__indicators .carousel__indicator:nth-of-type(3) {
  opacity: 1;
}

.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(4):checked ~ .carousel__track {
  -webkit-transform: translateX(-300%);
          transform: translateX(-300%);
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(4):checked ~ .carousel__slide:nth-of-type(4) {
  transition: opacity 0.5s, -webkit-transform 0.5s;
  transition: opacity 0.5s, transform 0.5s;
  transition: opacity 0.5s, transform 0.5s, -webkit-transform 0.5s;
  top: 0;
  left: 0;
  right: 0;
  opacity: 1;
  -webkit-transform: scale(1);
          transform: scale(1);
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(4):checked ~ .carousel__controls:nth-of-type(4) {
  display: block;
  opacity: 1;
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(4):checked ~ .carousel__indicators .carousel__indicator:nth-of-type(4) {
  opacity: 1;
}

.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(5):checked ~ .carousel__track {
  -webkit-transform: translateX(-400%);
          transform: translateX(-400%);
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(5):checked ~ .carousel__slide:nth-of-type(5) {
  transition: opacity 0.5s, -webkit-transform 0.5s;
  transition: opacity 0.5s, transform 0.5s;
  transition: opacity 0.5s, transform 0.5s, -webkit-transform 0.5s;
  top: 0;
  left: 0;
  right: 0;
  opacity: 1;
  -webkit-transform: scale(1);
          transform: scale(1);
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(5):checked ~ .carousel__controls:nth-of-type(5) {
  display: block;
  opacity: 1;
}
.carousel__activator:nth-of-type(5):checked ~ .carousel__indicators .carousel__indicator:nth-of-type(5) {
  opacity: 1;
}


.carousel__control {
  height: 30px;
  width: 30px;
  margin-top: -15px;
  top: 50%;
  position: absolute;
  display: block;
  cursor: pointer;
  border-width: 5px 5px 0 0;
  border-style: solid;
  border-color: #fafafa;
  opacity: 0.35;
  opacity: 1;
  outline: 0;
  z-index: 3;
}
.carousel__control:hover {
  opacity: 1;
}
.carousel__control--backward {
  left: 20px;
  -webkit-transform: rotate(-135deg);
          transform: rotate(-135deg);
}
.carousel__control--forward {
  right: 20px;
  -webkit-transform: rotate(45deg);
          transform: rotate(45deg);
}
.carousel__indicators {
  position: absolute;
  bottom: 20px;
  width: 100%;
  text-align: center;
}
.carousel__indicator {
  height: 15px;
  width: 15px;
  border-radius: 100%;
  display: inline-block;
  z-index: 2;
  cursor: pointer;
  opacity: 0.35;
  margin: 0 2.5px 0 2.5px;
}
.carousel__indicator:hover {
  opacity: 0.75;
}
.carousel__track {
  position: absolute;
  top: 0;
  right: 0;
  bottom: 0;
  left: 0;
  padding: 0;
  margin: 0;
  transition: -webkit-transform 0.5s ease 0s;
  transition: transform 0.5s ease 0s;
  transition: transform 0.5s ease 0s, -webkit-transform 0.5s ease 0s;
}
.carousel__track .carousel__slide {
  display: block;
  top: 0;
  left: 0;
  right: 0;
  opacity: 1;
}

.carousel__track .carousel__slide:nth-of-type(1) {
  -webkit-transform: translateX(000%);
          transform: translateX(000%);
}

.carousel__track .carousel__slide:nth-of-type(2) {
  -webkit-transform: translateX(100%);
          transform: translateX(100%);
}

.carousel__track .carousel__slide:nth-of-type(3) {
  -webkit-transform: translateX(200%);
          transform: translateX(200%);
}

.carousel__track .carousel__slide:nth-of-type(4) {
  -webkit-transform: translateX(300%);
          transform: translateX(300%);
}

.carousel__track .carousel__slide:nth-of-type(5) {
  -webkit-transform: translateX(400%);
          transform: translateX(400%);
}


.carousel--scale .carousel__slide {
  -webkit-transform: scale(0);
          transform: scale(0);
}
.carousel__slide {
  height: 100%;
  position: absolute;
  opacity: 0;
  overflow: hidden;
}
.carousel__slide .overlay {height: 100%;}
.carousel--thumb .carousel__indicator {
  height: 30px;
  width: 30px;
}
.carousel__indicator {
  background-color: #fafafa;
}

.carousel__slide:nth-of-type(1),
.carousel--thumb .carousel__indicators .carousel__indicator:nth-of-type(1) {
  background-size: cover;
  background-position: center;
}

.carousel__slide:nth-of-type(2),
.carousel--thumb .carousel__indicators .carousel__indicator:nth-of-type(2) {
  background-size: cover;
  background-position: center;
}

.carousel__slide:nth-of-type(3),
.carousel--thumb .carousel__indicators .carousel__indicator:nth-of-type(3) {
  background-size: cover;
  background-position: center;
}

.carousel__slide:nth-of-type(4),
.carousel--thumb .carousel__indicators .carousel__indicator:nth-of-type(4) {
  background-size: cover;
  background-position: center;
}

.carousel__slide:nth-of-type(5),
.carousel--thumb .carousel__indicators .carousel__indicator:nth-of-type(5) {
  background-size: cover;
  background-position: center;
}

&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Picture Credits: &lt;a href=&quot;https://appmech.nitk.ac.in/faculty/pruthviraj-u&quot;&gt;Prof. Pruthiviraj Umesh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>[&quot;shravan&quot;, &quot;mishal&quot;]</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="hackverse" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Congratulations on getting selected for HackVerse ‘20!</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Welcome HackVerse</title>
      <link href="/blog/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome HackVerse" />
      <published>2019-11-16T10:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-11-16T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/welcome</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/welcome">&lt;p&gt;NITK, Surathkal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page is still being edited covering the story behind HackVerse!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do join our Telegram Channel to meet an awesome community of hackers: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/hackverse&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Mishal Shah</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="hackverse" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">NITK, Surathkal!</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
